Guide to the Herbert Aptheker Papers, 1842-1999, (bulk 1934-1994)
Department of Special Collections
- Series 3. Printed Materials
  - Subseries D. Pamphlets
    - Levilain, Guy Viet. Cultural identity, negritude, and decolonization: the Haitian situation in the light of the socialist humanism of Jacques Roman and Rene Depestre. -- (Occasional paper, no. 29). -- New York: AIMS, 1978 (Box 151, Folder 16)
    - Lowenfels, Walter. We are all poets, really. -- Buffalo: Intrepid Press,, 1967 [1968] (Box 151, Folder 17)
    - Marti, Jose. La guerra social en Chicago. -- Montevideo: Ediciones America Nueva,, n.d. (Box 151, Folder 18)
    - Marti, Jose. The social war in Chicago / Jose Marti; trans. by R. Frankenburg; intro. & notes by P.S. Foner, n.d., tms (47 p.) (Box 151, Folder 19)
    - The Marxian. -- Vol. 1, no. 1, 1921 Oct. (Box 151, Folder 20)
    - Maryland. Governor's Commission on Problems Affecting the Negro Population. Record, 1943 Mar., 1 v. (145 p.) (Box 151, Folder 21)
    - Mayo, Selz C. Negro hospital and medical care facilities in North Carolina. -- Raleigh, N.C.: North Carolina Agricultural Experiment Station,, 1945 Apr. (Box 152, Folder 1)
    - McCoy, Ralph E. History of labor and unionism in the United States. -- (Bibliographic contributions, no. 2). -- Champaign, Ill.: Univ. of Illinois. Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations,, 1953 (Box 152, Folder 2)
    - McPherson, James M. White liberals and Black power in Negro education, 1865-1915. -- Reprinted from American Historical Review. -- Vol. 75, no. 5, 1970 June (Box 152, Folder 3)
    - McWilliams, Carey. Minority groups in the United States. -- Reprintedfrom ORT Economic Review,, 1944 Aug. (Box 152, Folder 4)
    - Mendelsohn, Isaac. Legal aspects of slavery in Babylonia, Assyria, and Palestine: a comparative study (300-500 B.C.). -- Williamsport, Va.: Bayard Press,, 1932 (Box 152, Folder 5)
    - Mitchell, James B. The collapse of the National Benefit Life Insurance Company: a study in high finance among Negroes. -- (Howard University Studies in the Social Sciences, Vol. II, no. 1). -- Washington, D.C.: Howard Univ., 1939 (Box 152, Folder 6)
    - Molyneaux, Lambert. Differential mortality in Virginia. -- Charlottesville, Va.: Univ. of Virginia. Bureau of Population and Economic Research,, 1947 (Box 152, Folder 7)
    - Montagu, M.F. Ashley. The concept of race in the human species in the light of genetics. -- Reprint from The Journal of Heredity. -- Vol. 32, 1941 (Box 152, Folder 8)
    - Montagu, M.F. Ashley. The creative power of ethnic mixture. -- Reprinted from Psychiatry. -- Vol. 5, no. 4, 1942 Nov. (Box 152, Folder 9)
    - Montagu, M.F. Ashley. The myth of blood. -- Reprinted from Psychiatry. -- Vol. 6, no. 1, 1943 Feb. (Box 152, Folder 10)
    - Montagu, M.F. Ashley. On the phrase "ethnic group" in anthropology. -- Reprinted from Psychiatry. -- Vol. 8, no. 1, 1945 Feb. (Box 152, Folder 11)
    - Montagu, M.F. Ashley. Origins of the American Negro. -- Reprinted from Psychiatry. -- Vol. 7, no. 2, 1944 May (Box 152, Folder 12)
    - Montagu, M.F. Ashley. The physical anthropology of the American Negro. -- Reprinted from Psychiatry. -- Vol. 7, no. 1, 1944 Feb. (Box 152, Folder 13)
    - Morgan, Patricia. Shame of a nation: a documented story of police-state terror against Mexican-Americans in the USA. -- Los Angeles: Los Angeles Committee for Protection of Foreign Born,, 1954 (Box 152, Folder 14)
    - Morrow, J.J. American negroes: a wasted resource. -- Reprinted from Harvard Business Review, 1957 Jan. - Feb. (Box 152, Folder 15)
    - Moser, Edwin M. Prelude to '60: the schism of the New York City democracy, 1844-1848, n.d., tms (Box 152, Folder 16)
    - NAACP. the fortieth year in the crusade for civil rights: NAACP annual report for 1948. -- New York: National Association for the Advancement of Colored People,, 1948 (Box 152, Folder 17)
    - NAACP. Miscellaneous pamphlets,, 1924 - 1927 (Box 152, Folder 18)
    - NAACP - American Interracial Peace Committee pamphlets, 1928 (Box 152, Folder 19)
    - NAACP. Segregation in government department, 1928 (Box 152, Folder 20)
    - National Council of the League of Struggle for Human Rights. Equality, land, and freedom: a program for Negro liberation. -- New York: The League,, 1933 (Box 152, Folder 21)
    - National Student Federation of American announces a student delegation to Soviet Russia,, 1927 (Box 152, Folder 22)
    - National Urban League. Freedom's seed: annual report,, 1943 (Box 152, Folder 23)
    - The Navy and the Massie-Kahahawai case. -- Honolulu, Hi: Honolulu Record Publishing Co.,, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 24)
    - The Negro: a list of significant books / comp. by Dorothy R. Homer and Evelyn R. Robinson. -- New York: The Public Library,, 1955 (Box 152, Folder 25)
    - Negro Year book: an annual encyclopedia of the Negro, 1914-1915, 1915 (Box 153, Folder 1)
    - Nelson, Dennis Denmark. The integration of the Negro in the United States Navy, 1776-1947. -- Thesis (M.A.). -- Howard University,, 1948 (Box 153, Folder 2)
    - New Jersey (State). Fifth annual report of the Good-will Commission to the Governor and the Legislature of the State of New Jersey,, 1943 Sept. 1 - 1944 Sept. 1 (Box 153, Folder 3)
    - New Jersey (State). Dept. of Education. Division against Racism. miscellaneous documents (Box 153, Folder 4)
    - O'Connor, Tom. The origin of the Sacco-Vanzetti case. -- Reprinted from the Vanderbilt Law Review. -- Vol. 14, no. 3, 1961 June (Box 153, Folder 5)
    - Osagyefo. Speech at the opening session of the First meeting of the editorial board of the Encyclopedia Africana, Univ. of Ghana,, 1964 Sept. 24, tms (9 p.) (Box 153, Folder 6)
    - Padmore, George, ed. Colonial and colored unity: a programme of action: history of the Pan-African Congress. -- Manchester, England: The Pan-African Federation,, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 7)
    - Paul Robeson Committee of the German Democratic Republic Award, 1980 Mar. 27 (Box 153, Folder 8)
    - Preece, Harold. Peonage: 1940 style slavery. -- Chicago: Abolish Peonage Committee,, 1940 (Box 153, Folder 9)
    - Proceedings of the sixteenth annual conference of the Presidents of Negro Land Grant colleges,, 1938 Nov. 14-16 (Box 153, Folder 10)
    - Proceedings of the nineteenth annual conference of the Presidents of Negro Land Grant colleges,, 1941 Nov. 11-13 (Box 153, Folder 11)
    - Proceedings of the twenty-second annual conference of the Presidents of Negro Land Grant colleges,, 1944 Oct. 24-26 (Box 153, Folder 12)
    - Psychiatric aspects of social desegregation. -- (Report no. 37). -- New York: Group of the Advancement of Psychiatry,, 1957 (Box 153, Folder 13)
    - Race Relations Law Reporter. -- Vol. 1, no. 1, 1956 Feb. (Box 153, Folder 14)
    - Race Relations Law Reporter. -- Vol. 1, no. 2, 1956 Apr. (Box 154, Folder 1)
    - Race Relations Law Reporter. -- Vol. 1, no. 3, 1956 June (Box 154, Folder 2)
    - Race Relations Law Reporter. -- Vol. 1, no. 4, 1956 Aug. (Box 154, Folder 3)
    - Reckford, Mary. The Jamaica slave rebellion of 1831. -- Reprinted from Past & Present, 1968 July (Box 154, Folder 4)
    - Reference of Southern Colored schools. -- (Trustees of the John F. Slater Fund, no. 20), 1921 (Box 154, Folder 5)
    - Renaissance - Bauernkrieg - Reformation Kolloquium, 1975 Jan. 21-23 (Box 154, Folder 6)
    - Rhea, James N. Bulge in the color line. -- Reprinted from the Providence Journal and Evening Bulletin, 1953 Mar. - Apr. (Box 154, Folder 7)
    - Rippy, J. Fred. Joel R. Poinsett, versatile American,, 1959 Mar. 24, tms (11 p.) (Box 154, Folder 8)
    - Schleuter, Herman. Abraham Lincoln and the working class. -- (People's Pocket Series, no. 159). -- Girard, Kan.: Appeal to Reason,, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 9)
    - Spivak, John L. On the chain gang. -- (International Pamphlets, no. 32). -- [S.l.: s.n.], n.d. (Box 154, Folder 10)
    - Stern, Celia. Children's literature and the Negro stereotype. -- New York: Bureau for Intercultural Education,, 1945 (Box 154, Folder 11)
    - Stewart, Maxwell S. The negro in America. -- (Public Affairs pamphlet, no. 95). -- New York: Public Affairs Committee,, 1944 (Box 154, Folder 12)
    - Stewart, Maxwell S. Prejudice in textbooks. -- [New York]: Public Affairs Committee,, 1950 (Box 154, Folder 13)
    - The story of discrimination in government. -- (Publication no. 125). -- New York: United Public Workers of America, CIO,, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 14)
    - Stoughton, Amanda L. and Mary Gover. A study of Negro infant mortality. -- (Reprint no. 1331). -- Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office,, 1929 (Box 154, Folder 15)
    - To abolish discrimination. -- Washington, D.C.: National CIO Committee to Abolish Discrimination,, 1947 Mar. (Box 154, Folder 16)
    - To be Black in America: a selected bibliography. -- Philadelphia: The Free Library,, [1970?] (Box 154, Folder 17)
    - To stamp out discrimination: a handbook. -- Detroit, Mich.: International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America (UAW-CIO),, [1944] (Box 154, Folder 18)
    - UNESCO land its programme III: the race question. -- [Paris]: UNESCO,, 1950 (Box 154, Folder 19)
    - University of Massachusetts Press. Fall & Winter books, 1976 (Box 154, Folder 20)
    - University of Massachusetts Press. Spring & Summer books, 1976 (Box 154, Folder 21)
    - Van Til, William. The work of the Bureau for International Exchange. -- (Work in Progress Series). -- New York: Bureau for Intercultural Education,, ca. 1945 (Box 154, Folder 22)
    - Walters, Pat. Encounter with the future. -- Atlanta: Southern Regional Council,, 1965 (Box 154, Folder 23)
    - Weiss, Jeffrey John. How mainstream media report political dissent. -- Thesis (M.A.). -- Iowa State University, 1993 (Box 154, Folder 24)
    - Wilson, H.H. The modd of the nation, Nov. 22-29, 1963: a news documentary of a steadfast citizenry, with an appraisal. -- New York: Marzini & Mansell,, 1963 (Box 154, Folder 25)
    - Wirzberger, Karl-Heinz. Probleme der burgerrechtsbewegung in der Amerikanischen prosaliteratur der Gegenwart, 1967, 36 p. (Box 154, Folder 26)
    - Wolpin, Miles D. United States intervention in Latin America: a selected and annotated bibliography. -- (Bibliographical series, no. 8). -- New York: AIMS,, 1971 (Box 154, Folder 27)
    - Your civil rights: a handbook for trade union members and organizers. -- Washington, D.C.: Congress of Industrial Organizations,, [1946] (Box 154, Folder 28)
    - Untitled manuscript, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 29)
- Series 4. Family Papers
  Contains correspondence between Herbert and Fay Aptheker and correspondence from Bettina Aptheker and her parents. Also contains extensive clippings on the activities of Bettina Aptheker as well as copies of her articles from grade school through her adult career as an academic. This series also includes memorabilia of all three family members, as well as a history of the Aptheker family written by Fay Aptheker.
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1939 (Box 155, Folder 1)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1941 (Box 155, Folder 2)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 Feb. (Box 155, Folder 3)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 Mar. 1-23 (Box 155, Folder 4)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 Mar. 24-31 (Box 155, Folder 5)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 Apr. (Box 155, Folder 6)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 May 1-15 (Box 155, Folder 7)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 May 16-30 (Box 155, Folder 8)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 June 1-15 (Box 155, Folder 9)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 June 16-30 (Box 155, Folder 10)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 July 1-15 (Box 155, Folder 11)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 July 16-31 (Box 155, Folder 12)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 Aug. 1-10 (Box 155, Folder 13)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 Aug. 11-20 (Box 155, Folder 14)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 Aug. 21-28 (Box 155, Folder 15)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 Sept. 1-15 (Box 155, Folder 16)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 Sept. 16-28 (Box 155, Folder 17)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1942 Nov. - Dec. (Box 156, Folder 1)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1943 Jan. - June (Box 156, Folder 2)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1943 Aug. - Dec. (Box 156, Folder 3)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1944 (Box 156, Folder 4)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 Jan. (Box 156, Folder 5)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 Feb. (Box 156, Folder 6)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 Mar. 1-15 (Box 156, Folder 7)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 Mar. 16-31 (Box 156, Folder 8)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 Apr. (Box 156, Folder 9)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 May 1-20 (Box 156, Folder 10)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 May 21-31 (Box 156, Folder 11)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 June 1-18 (Box 156, Folder 12)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 June 19-30 (Box 156, Folder 13)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 July 1-10 (Box 156, Folder 14)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 July 11-31 (Box 157, Folder 1)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 Aug. - Sept. (Box 157, Folder 2)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 Oct. (Box 157, Folder 3)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 Nov. 1-8 (Box 157, Folder 4)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 Nov. 16-25 (Box 157, Folder 5)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 Nov. 26-30 (Box 157, Folder 6)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 Dec. 1-7 (Box 157, Folder 7)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 Dec. 8-18 (Box 157, Folder 8)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1945 Dec. 19-31 (Box 157, Folder 9)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1946 Jan. 1-10 (Box 157, Folder 10)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1946 Jan. 11-19 (Box 157, Folder 11)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1946 Jan. 21-31 (Box 157, Folder 12)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1946 Feb. (Box 157, Folder 13)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1946 Apr. - Nov. (Box 157, Folder 14)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1947 Feb. (Box 158, Folder 1)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1947 Mar. - Apr. (Box 158, Folder 2)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1947 Nov. (Box 158, Folder 3)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1948 Feb. (Box 158, Folder 4)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1948 June - July (Box 158, Folder 5)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1948 Aug. - Sept. (Box 158, Folder 6)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1949 (Box 158, Folder 7)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1950 (Box 158, Folder 8)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1951 (Box 158, Folder 9)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1952 (Box 158, Folder 10)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1953 - 1954 (Box 158, Folder 11)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1955 (Box 158, Folder 12)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1960 (Box 158, Folder 13)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1962 (Box 158, Folder 14)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1963 (Box 158, Folder 15)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1964 (Box 158, Folder 16)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1965 (Box 158, Folder 17)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1966 (Box 158, Folder 18)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1967 (Box 159, Folder 1)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1968 (Box 159, Folder 2)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1969 (Box 159, Folder 3)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1970 (Box 159, Folder 4)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1971 (Box 159, Folder 5)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1972 (Box 159, Folder 6)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1974 (Box 159, Folder 7)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, 1975 (Box 159, Folder 8)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Fay Aptheker, n.d. (Box 159, Folder 9)
  - Herbert Aptheker correspondence to Bettina Aptheker, 1955 - 1970 (Box 159, Folder 10)
  - Herbert and Fay Aptheker correspondence to Bettina Aptheker, 1961 (Box 159, Folder 11)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1960 June - Aug. (Box 159, Folder 12)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1962 Sept. (Box 159, Folder 13)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1962 Oct. (Box 159, Folder 14)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1962 Nov. (Box 159, Folder 15)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1962 Dec. (Box 159, Folder 16)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1963 Jan. (Box 159, Folder 17)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1963 Feb. (Box 159, Folder 18)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1963 Mar. 1-15 (Box 160, Folder 1)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1963 Mar. 16-31 (Box 160, Folder 2)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1963 Apr. (Box 160, Folder 3)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1963 May (Box 160, Folder 4)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1963 June (Box 160, Folder 5)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1963 July - Aug. (Box 160, Folder 6)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1963 Sept. (Box 160, Folder 7)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1963 Oct. (Box 160, Folder 8)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1963 Nov. (Box 160, Folder 9)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1963 Dec. (Box 160, Folder 10)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1964 Jan. (Box 160, Folder 11)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1964 Feb. (Box 160, Folder 12)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1964 Mar. (Box 160, Folder 13)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1964 Apr. - May (Box 160, Folder 14)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1964 June - Aug. (Box 161, Folder 1)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1964 Sept. - Oct. (Box 161, Folder 2)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1964 Nov. - Dec. (Box 161, Folder 3)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1965 Jan. - Feb. (Box 161, Folder 4)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1965 Mar. - Apr. (Box 161, Folder 5)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1965 May - June (Box 161, Folder 6)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1965 July (Box 161, Folder 7)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1965 Aug. - Oct. (Box 161, Folder 8)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1965 Nov. - Dec. (Box 161, Folder 9)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1966 Jan. (Box 161, Folder 10)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1966 Feb. - Apr. (Box 161, Folder 11)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1966 May - July (Box 161, Folder 12)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1966 Aug. - Oct. (Box 161, Folder 13)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1966 Nov. - Dec. (Box 161, Folder 14)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1967 Jan. - June (Box 162, Folder 1)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1967 July - Dec. (Box 162, Folder 2)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1968 Jan. - June (Box 162, Folder 3)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1968 July - Dec. (Box 162, Folder 4)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1969 (Box 162, Folder 5)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1970 Jan. - Sept. (Box 162, Folder 6)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1970 Oct. - Dec. (Box 162, Folder 7)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1971 Jan. - June (Box 162, Folder 8)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1971 July - Dec. (Box 162, Folder 9)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1972 Jan. - Mar. (Box 162, Folder 10)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1972 Apr. - Dec. (Box 162, Folder 11)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1973 Jan. - Mar. (Box 162, Folder 12)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1973 Apr. - June (Box 163, Folder 1)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1973 July - Sept. (Box 163, Folder 2)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1973 Oct. - Dec. (Box 163, Folder 3)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1974 Jan. - Mar. (Box 163, Folder 4)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1974 Apr. - June (Box 163, Folder 5)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1974 July - Dec. (Box 163, Folder 6)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1975 (Box 163, Folder 7)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1976 Jan. - Feb. (Box 163, Folder 8)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1976 Apr. - Sept. (Box 163, Folder 9)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1976 Oct. - Dec. (Box 163, Folder 10)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1977 (Box 163, Folder 11)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1978 (Box 163, Folder 12)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1980 Jan. - Apr. (Box 163, Folder 13)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1980 May - Dec. (Box 163, Folder 14)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1981 - 1982 (Box 163, Folder 15)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1983 (Box 163, Folder 16)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1984 (Box 163, Folder 17)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1985 Jan. - Mar. (Box 164, Folder 1)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1985 Apr. - June (Box 164, Folder 2)
  - Bettina Aptheker correspondence to Herbert and Fay Aptheker, 1985 Aug. - Oct. (Box 164, Folder 3)